The strings are
文字列は
just like the backdid new
まるで新品のように
and that's the place
そしてそこがその場所です
where we call stone walking.
ここを私たちはストーンウォーキングと呼んでいます。
Yeah, you can follow
はい、フォローしてもいいですよ
their walk using partright
パートライトを使った彼らの散歩
here on your channel.
あなたのチャンネルのここにあります。
They won't accept
彼らは受け入れないだろう
your cause,
あなたの原因、
but,
しかし、
security means
安全手段
you just have
あなたはちょうど持っています
cheek
頬
good night friends
おやすみ、友達
I'm actually here to fight today.
実は今日は戦いに来たんです。
Because it turned out that Vice President Wang Fansheng was going to preside over the
主催者は王範生副総統が務める予定だったからだ。
But he just happened to be leaving the country.
しかし、彼はたまたま出国するところだった。
So let me, a layman, do this as the moderator
そこで、素人の私が司会者としてやらせていただきます
Today we are very happy to have invited researcher Zhang Zhenghua
今日は研究者の張正華さんをお招きできてとても嬉しいです
He's a researcher at our fish lab.
彼は私たちの魚研究所の研究員です。
I just talked to him a little while ago and he has a very long history
先ほど彼と話したばかりですが、彼は非常に長い歴史を持っています
All thirty years of researcher experience in Piscivora
Piscivora での 30 年にわたる研究者の経験すべて
Researcher Zhang is currently a researcher of our Central Research Institute
張研究員は現在、中央研究所の研究員です。
is also a researcher in archeology at our Center for Human Design
ヒューマンデザインセンターの考古学の研究者でもあります
About the CEO of Album Center
アルバムセンター代表取締役社長
He is also from the Department of Anthropology of Tsinghua University
彼は清華大学人類学部の出身でもあります。
adjunct professor combined
非常勤教授兼任
Dr. Zhang graduated from Harvard University
チャン博士はハーバード大学を卒業しました
just chatted
ただチャットしただけ
I just found out when he was studying at Harvard
彼がハーバード大学に留学していたときに知りました
I'm also building bridges
橋も架けています
This place in Maryland
メリーランド州のこの場所
Although in the same city
同じ市内なのに
But I didn't know much at that time
でも当時はあまり知識がなかったので
so happy now
今はとても幸せです
I know Researcher Zhang also stayed at Harvard
張研究員もハーバード大学に残ったことは知っています
Teacher Zhang's expertise
張先生の専門知識
in archaeology, of course
もちろん考古学で
especially many recent
特に最近多い
Especially some archaeological ones under the waters
特に海底にある考古学的なもの
This topic is very researched
このトピックは非常に研究されています
His academic experience is very rich
彼の学業経験は非常に豊富です
Then in our research
それから私たちの研究では
He also served as the deputy director of domestic research institutes
国内研究機関の副所長も務めた
But he is the curator of the National Taiwan Museum of Prehistoric Culture
しかし、彼は国立台湾先史文化博物館の学芸員です。
that one is in Taitung
あれは台東にあります
i visited twice
私は2回訪れました
is a very nice place
とても素敵な場所です
Well, I also held many important positions in this National Science Council.
さて、私もこの国家学術会議で多くの重要な役職を歴任しました。
Now he is also the director of Anthropology and Ethnology
現在、彼は人類学および民族学のディレクターでもあります
chairman of the society
協会の会長
Chairman of the Chinese School Archeology Society
中国学校考古学協会会長
International Indo-China
国際インドシナ
The president of the Bhistory Association, etc.
歴史協会会長など。
So this academic manager is indeed very rich
つまり、この学術マネージャーは確かに非常に裕福です
Then I won the Contact Award from the National Science Council.
その後、全米学術会議からコンタクト賞を受賞しました。
This Wu Sanlian award and so on
今回の呉三蓮賞など
so today we are happy
だから今日私たちは幸せです
This can invite Dr. Zhang to come here
これは張博士をここに招待することができます
Tell us about the test results in the Taiwan waters
台湾海域での試験結果について教えてください
So today I'm here to host
それで今日は私がホストをするためにここに来ました
feast of knowledge
知識の饗宴
Come to fill up once
一度給油しに来てください
I have presided over a lot of life sciences
多くの生命科学を主宰してきました
rarely fully booked
満席になることはほとんどありません
I am very happy to have a warm state today
今日は暖かくてとても嬉しいです
So we can also expect
したがって、私たちも期待できます
his speech is rich
彼のスピーチは豊かだ
I heard he has 190 slides
彼は190枚のスライドを持っていると聞きました
so we have an hour and a half
だから1時間半あるよ
see if he can finish
彼が完走できるかどうか見てみる
Less time to ask questions if you don't finish speaking
質問する時間が減る
We please warmly welcome our teacher Zhang
張先生を温かく迎え入れてください。
Vice President Wang
王副院長
And our colleagues in the hospital
そして病院の同僚たち
and my friends
そして私の友達
Goodnight everybody
おやすみ皆さん
I am honored today
今日は光栄です
it's not an honor
それは名誉なことではありません
It's the courtyard that ordered me to speak
私に話すよう命じたのは中庭だ
I had to give orders
命令を出さなければならなかった
let's make a report
報告をしましょう
When I was asked to report
報告を求められたとき
I asked what topic I was talking about
何の話題について話しているのか聞いてみた
I consider
私が検討します
Actually, I personally study archaeology.
実は私は個人的に考古学を勉強しています。
In fact, there are many topics that can be discussed
実際、議論できるトピックはたくさんあります
Because of archeology, our specialty is to go to the mountains and go to the sea.
考古学なので山に行くのも海に行くのも専門です。
So there are quite a lot of different themes.
そのため、さまざまなテーマがたくさんあります。
Later, I still chose this topic
その後、このトピックを選択しました
Because this topic is what we have been doing in recent years
このテーマは私たちが近年取り組んでいることであるため、
Moreover, it is actually a topic that has made substantial contributions to Taiwan.
また、実は台湾にとっても大きな貢献をしているテーマでもあります。
Because Taiwan is surrounded by sea
台湾は海に囲まれているので
Taiwan is surrounded by sea
台湾は海に囲まれている
But in this field, there was actually a blank in the past.
しかし、実はこの分野、過去にブランクがあったのです。
almost blank
ほぼ空白の
So we compare these countries around us
そこで私たちの周りの国を比較してみます
In fact, a lot behind
実際にはかなり遅れています
Our surroundings are like mainland Japan
私たちの周囲はまるで本土のようです
Shenger Philippines in Southeast Asia Vietnam in Thailand
シェンガー 東南アジアのフィリピン タイ タイのベトナム
They've done a lot of this
彼らはこれをたくさんやってきました
But our Taiwan is a blank
しかし、私たちの台湾は空白です
None so it's a zero
何もないのでゼロです
So in recent years this opportunity
そこで近年ではこの機会に
to take charge of such a job
そのような仕事を担当する
In fact, I personally feel terrified on the one hand.
実際、私自身も一方では恐怖を感じています。
On the other hand, I also feel that it is a sense of experimentation.
一方で、実験的な感覚も感じています。
I think
私が思うに
The vice president of our company in Academia Sinica just said that I have a long history
中央研究院の当社副所長が、私には長い歴史があると言いました。
So here I think it is necessary to make some contributions to the country.
したがって、ここで私は国に何らかの貢献をする必要があると思います。
Otherwise, I'm just messing around here like that.
そうでなければ、私はこのようにここをいじっているだけです。
So I just like to talk about this topic today
それで、今日はこのトピックについて話したいと思います
I also want to share with all our guests
ゲストの皆様にもお伝えしたいのですが、
Can come to share some of our work in recent years
近年の私たちの仕事の一部を共有するために来ることができます
Some preliminary results
いくつかの暫定的な結果
Well, of course, maybe our poster is too beautiful.
もちろん、私たちのポスターが美しすぎるかもしれません。
So then we attract so much of our audience
それで、私たちは多くの聴衆を魅了します
Ms. Huang, tell me the truth, give me an email saying
黄さん、本当のことを言って、次のようなメールをください。
Wow, what is the full report this time?
うわー、今回のレポートの全文は何ですか？
Then I said oh, I'm surprised
それから私は「ああ、驚いた」と言いました
Because in the past, our archaeological topics were all very cold farts.
なぜなら、かつては考古学的な話題はすべて非常に冷たい屁理屈だったからです。
Then it is very difficult to have an audience for this audience.
そうなると、この聴衆に聴衆を集めるのは非常に困難です。
Then I go to class and study again.
それから授業に行ってまた勉強します。
Probably the amount of inflation is two or three people or seven or eight people.
おそらくインフレの量は2、3人か7、8人です。
Ah, so there are so many people saying 250 people, I was shocked again
ああ、250人って言う人が多いのか、また衝撃を受けた
I'm also very glad that everyone is interested. Of course it's great.
皆さんが興味を持ってくださったこともとても嬉しいです、もちろんそれは素晴らしいことです。
so so so so not much time today
まあまあまあまあ今日はあまり時間がない
uh yes
ああ、そうだね
I prepared a lot of slides like this
こんな感じのスライドをたくさん用意しました
But I know time is unlimited
でも時間は無限だとわかっている
So I deleted some
なので一部削除しました
But I didn't notice that there are still so many
でもまだこんなにたくさんあるとは気づきませんでした
so i'll be soon
だからすぐに行きます
See how much you can talk like this
どれだけこのように話せるか見てみましょう
then this
それからこれ
So this underwater archeology
つまり、この水中考古学は
It's a word that sticks to this archeology
この考古学に刺さる言葉です
Therefore, in the common people's concept
したがって、庶民の概念では、
In fact, archeology is digging in the ground.
実際、考古学は地面を掘っています。
So just dig down
それで、ただ掘り下げてください
is archeology
考古学です
So the general idea is that terrestrial archaeology
一般的な考え方は、地球考古学です。
So I seldom think of doing archaeology in waters
だから私は水域で考古学をやろうとはほとんど思いません。
Well, so our archeology on land
そうですね、陸上における私たちの考古学は
In fact, up to millions of years
実際、何百万年にもわたって
then until modern times
その後現代に至るまで
In fact, it is also a time when we do archaeology.
実際、考古学を行う時期でもあります。
a category
カテゴリ
so like this
だからこのように
Everyone is a stereotype like these
みんなこんな固定観念あるんだな
Those who go to archaeology are doing monuments.
考古学に行く人は記念碑の研究をしています。
Japan's this
日本はこれだ
some say
ある人は言う
actually
実際
Those people are reformers
あの人たちは改革者だ
But it turns out to be a post
でも虽然是针像
then proof
それから証明する
And it's still kinda cool
そしてまだ素晴らしい
That UNGYA special treasure
ウンギャの特別な宝物
Anyway, look at it as a
とにかく、それを見てください
just started coming out like that
ちょうどそのように出始めたばかりです
show scene
ショーシーン
a little small
少し小さい
kind of
すこし
prepare for seat
席の準備をする
to find
見つけるには
will definitely come out later
必ず後で出てくるだろう
promote can also
促進することもできます
From this next
この次からは
this maya this mexican
このマヤ、このメキシコ人
These Pyramids from Astic
アスティックのピラミッド
and these things
そしてこれらのこと
In fact, Huang's bima swims
実際、黄さんのビマは泳ぎます
And these childlike, jade-like
そして、これらの子供っぽい、翡翠のような
these things
これらの事
Well in fact
まあ実際のところ
For the last forty or fifty years now
ここ40年か50年くらいの間、
In fact, now everyone is starting to notice
実は今、誰もが気づき始めている
In fact, archeology is not just on the road
実際、考古学はただ進んでいるだけではありません
actually in the water
実は水の中
In fact, there are many, many
実際には、たくさんあります
Remnants of some human cultures
いくつかの人間文化の名残
What about these remains?
これらの遺跡はどうなるのでしょうか？
its quantity its value
その量その価値
Definitely not faster than on land
陸上より全然速くない
Although there are pyramids on land
地上にはピラミッドがあるのに
But there are also pyramids in the water
しかし、水中にはピラミッドもあります
There are many precious things in the water
水の中には大切なものがたくさんある
of these cultures
これらの文化の
remains of human culture
人間の文化の遺跡
its importance is very important
その重要性は非常に重要です
And all the waters of the earth
そして地球上のすべての水は
take up our entire planet
私たちの地球全体を占める
Three quarters of the earth is water
地球の4分の3は水
Only a quarter of the land is occupied by land
土地の4分の1だけが土地で占められています
maritime
海上
In fact, so in the sea
実は海でもそうなんです
It can be said that it is a very colorful underwater world
水中世界はとてもカラフルだと言えます
So the ocean it doesn't just have
だから海はただあるだけではない
These are beautiful underwater style
美しい水中スタイルですね
Because of these coral reefs and so on
このサンゴ礁などのせいで
In fact, there are still a considerable number of these human cultural relics in the sea.
実際、こうした人類の文化遺物は今も海中に相当数残っている。
Of course, on the one hand, some of these relics were deliberately left behind by humans.
もちろん一方で、これらの遺物の中には人間が意図的に残したものもあります。
Some are sunk into the sea due to the rise or change of the water level.
水位の上昇や変化により海に沈んでしまうものもあります。
Of course, some of them entered by accident.
もちろん、中には偶然入った人もいます。
Like a plane crash, the plane just fell into the sea, right?
飛行機事故みたいに、飛行機が海に落ちただけですよね？
So there are actually a lot of these things in our sea area
つまり、私たちの海域には実際にこれらのものがたくさんあります
Then these things also need to do some archaeology
そうすると、これらのことも考古学を行う必要がある
The so-called archeology is not an old treasure
いわゆる考古学は古い宝物ではありません
It is a scientific and systematic way to do some research and a collection
これは、調査と収集を行うための科学的かつ体系的な方法です。
So we actually have all kinds of relics of human culture from the sea
つまり、私たちは実際に海からあらゆる種類の人類文化の遺物を持っているのです
Strange, this is a topic we are familiar with recently
奇妙なことに、これは私たちが最近よく知っている話題です
overall climate change
全体的な気候変動
climate warming
気候温暖化
so one day
それである日
This scenario may arise
こういうシナリオが起こるかもしれない
look at these cities now
今これらの都市を見てください
Maybe in the sea in the future
もしかしたら将来は海の中にいるかもしれない
if one day in the future
いつか将来のことなら
It must be exciting to do underwater archaeology
水中考古学をやるのは刺激的でしょうね
you see this is a
これはわかりますか
If the sea level rises two meters
海面が２メートル上昇すると
this is new york
ここはニューヨークです
This is what a space in New York looks like
ニューヨークの空間はこうなる
So it's not really impossible
だから実際には不可能ではない
In the future these so-called legacies of humanity
将来、これらのいわゆる人類の遺産は、
These heritages that will become underwater in the future
将来海底に沈むこれらの遺産
So underwater is actually a
したがって、水中は実際には
Implicit responsibilities, let's do some discussion
暗黙の責任、少し議論しましょう
So in this underwater heritage
この水中遺産では
In fact, there are various categories
実は色々なカテゴリーがあるのですが、
I just said there are buildings
建物があるって言っただけだよ
city ​​with a past
過去のある街
Carved castle with a past
過去を刻んだ城
There are villages and towns
村もあれば町もある
But there's a whole lot more
しかし、それ以外にもたくさんあります
what is p by boat
ボートでのpは何ですか
The number of boats is quite abundant
船の数はかなり豊富です
more than vietnam
ベトナム以上に
This image is from Google Earth
この画像は Google Earth からのものです
each of these little blue dots
これらの小さな青い点の一つ一つが
Just looking at the Earth from space
宇宙から地球を眺めるだけ
The ruins of these boats that can be seen
見えるこの船の残骸
Of course, most of these boat rides are in shallow seas
もちろん、これらのボート乗りのほとんどは浅い海で行われます。
or near the sea
または海の近く
So it can be seen that this shipwreck
したがって、この難破船は
after it marks it
それをマークした後
you are everywhere
あなたはどこにでもいます
So this number can be said to be quite large
したがって、この数字はかなり大きいと言えます
So of course there are more under the sea
もちろん海中にはもっとたくさんあります
can zoom in a bit
少しズームできます
you can look at these
これらを見ることができます
You see these are secret codes
これらは秘密のコードだということがわかります
not just in the sea
海の中だけではなく
In land rivers and lakes
陸の川や湖では
There are also many, many of these ancient boats
このような古代の船もたくさんあります
the most famous one by boat
ボートで行く最も有名なもの
Everybody knows
誰もが知っている
Do you all know each other?
皆さんはお互いを知っていますか？
Titanic Anne
タイタニック・アン
At this time the most famous
この時点で最も有名なのは
The whole world probably talks about taking a boat
おそらく世界中がボートに乗ることについて話しているでしょう
don't even mention this one
これについても言及しないでください
So what about the city ship after the silence of 1912
では、1912 年の沈黙の後、市の船はどうなったのでしょうか
Then it exists in the North Atlantic Ocean below 3000 meters
その後、北大西洋の水深3000メートル以下に存在します
Then came 1985
そして1985年が来た
It was only discovered by this man's chest
この男の胸によってのみ発見された
He came from this state of Massachusetts in the United States
彼はアメリカのマサチューセッツ州の出身です
a physicist
物理学者
Then he invented this underwater submersible
それから彼はこの水中潜水艇を発明しました
so go down in the water
だから水に沈んでください
To be able to capture this image of Titanic
タイタニック号のこの画像を撮影できるなんて
Of course this is a very famous city ship
もちろん、これは非常に有名な都市船です
Well, of course his value is being discussed a lot now
もちろん、彼の価値については現在多くの議論が行われています
because he was 1912
彼は1912年だったから
His age is close to 100 years from now
他的年代距離現在接近100年
less than 100 years old
100歳未満
So what is his worth?
それで、彼の価値は何ですか？
So now in the US, UK, France, Canada
現在、米国、英国、フランス、カナダでは
So he's debating what the hell to do with this city ship
それで彼はこの都市の船を一体どうするか議論している
Of course many commercial businessmen
もちろん多くの商業ビジネスマンも
to salvage these things
これらのものを救い出すために
Because he has too many magical legends
魔法の伝説が多すぎるから
So I want to fish for the treasures inside and sell them.
なので、中にあるお宝を釣り上げて売りたいと思っています。
do a business
ビジネスをする
But now in the United States they prevent such an act
しかし現在、米国ではそのような行為は禁止されています
He believes that this is still a very important cultural heritage of human beings
彼は、これが依然として人類の非常に重要な文化遺産であると信じています。
is a so-called memory
いわゆる思い出です
A very good historical memory of a human being
人間の非常に良い歴史的記憶
So we still have to find a way to legislate to protect this city ship
したがって、私たちはこの都市の船を保護するための法を制定する方法をまだ見つけなければなりません
so so why
それでなぜ
In fact, there are many cultural heritages of these human beings underwater.
実際、水中にはこうした人類の文化遺産が数多く残っています。
Many of them have very important historical or cultural values
その多くは非常に重要な歴史的または文化的価値を持っています
But why did we not do archaeology in the water in the past?
しかし、なぜ昔は水中で考古学をやらなかったのでしょうか?
The Pyramid we just saw
先ほど見たピラミッド
Egyptian pyramids
エジプトのピラミッド
This Bi Meiying of Qin Shihuang
この秦の始皇帝の碧美英
There are many other kinds on land
陸上には他にもたくさんの種類がいます
Why don't you go into the water and do archaeology?
水に入って考古学をしてみませんか？
right
右
In fact, you can't and you can't do it
実際、それはできないし、できない
In fact, humans have known for a long time that there are many treasures in the water
実際、人間は水の中にたくさんの宝物があることを長い間知っていました。
so he can't go down
だから彼は下がれない
because you mainly
なぜならあなたは主に
everyone because we know
みんな、私たちは知っているから
You hold your breath for two minutes and you're done.
2分間息を止めれば完了です。
So it's just not going down
だから下がらないだけだよ
In fact, human beings have been
実際、人類はこれまで、
Just a wish to dive into the water
ただ水に飛び込みたいという願いだけ
look at this
これを見てください
We have recorded in these ancient documents in China
私たちは中国のこれらの古文書に記録しています
as early as when bluestone was yellow
早くもブルーストーンイエロー
He knew there was a roof in the water
彼は水の中に屋根があることを知っていた
Because the ancient Chinese especially the rulers
なぜなら古代中国人、特に統治者は
Very important to this top
このトップにとって非常に重要
able to get the top
トップを獲得することができた
represents one of his powers
彼の力の一つを表します
become a real man
本物の男になる
So he has the top of the Zhou Dynasty
つまり彼は周王朝のトップにある
Of course you need to use Sishui Zhaozhao
もちろんSishui Zhaozhaoを使用する必要があります
What about Emperor Wu of the Han Dynasty?
漢の武帝はどうでしょうか？
his reign dome
彼の治世のドーム
he tops for some favorites
彼はいくつかのお気に入りのトップにいる
Divide the water
分水上
Got the top in this watershed
この流域でトップに立った
so they know the water has a lot of
だから彼らは水の中にたくさんのものがあることを知っています
something from the past is in it
過去の何かが入っている
so they want to find
だから彼らは見つけたいのです
What about the Greek philosopher?
ギリシャの哲学者はどうでしょうか？
What about Ariswold?
アリスウォルドはどうですか？
They also know the water
彼らは水のことも知っています
should go down and have a look
下に行って見るべきです
Why can't I go down?
なぜ下がれないのですか？
can't we breathe in?
息が吸えないの？
Immediately suffocated
すぐに窒息した
so he therefore
だから彼は
he is very smart
彼はとても賢い
He spoke of man's ability to turn bronze chests
彼は青銅の箱を回す人間の能力について話した
Put a bronze iron cabinet into the water
青銅の鉄のキャビネットを水の中に入れます
Then people inside can go to the iron cabinet
その後、中の人は鉄のキャビネットに行くことができます
It can use its residual air inside
内部の残留空気を利用できます
can come and dive into the water
来て水に飛び込むことができます
So this is a
これは
These
これらは
look at this
これを見てください
Humans are missing from these two pictures from antiquity
古代のこれら 2 枚の写真からは人間が欠けています
I suddenly managed to go
いつの間にか行けてた
that this
これは
this from
これから
From before the festival
お祭り前から
Until Jingguo entered the Qian century
経国が乾世紀に入るまで
Just trying to get into the water
ただ水に入ろうとしているだけ
look at it this is fun
見てください、これは楽しいです
it uses this thing to put it inside
これを使って中に入れます
go into the water
水の中へ入る
This is also a cabinet
こちらもキャビネットです
man inside through an air
空気を通して中の人
then put the air in
それから空気を入れます
then dive
それから潜る
then this is more fun
だったらこっちのほうが楽しいよ
he uses a bucket
彼はバケツを使います
people inside
中の人
Do you see it
あなた見えますか
Then this hand is outside
そうするとこの手は外にある
he can pick up things in it
彼はその中にあるものを拾うことができる
This is getting better and better
これはどんどん良くなってきています
have some strange ideas
いくつかの奇妙なアイデアを持っています
into the water to dive
水に潜って潜る
this is a
これは
this one came out
これが出てきた
This is at 900BC
これは紀元前900年のこと
Humans want to use this method
人間はこの方法を使いたがります
animal skin
動物の皮
Then pipe it into the
次に、パイプで
it can see through the air of the skin
皮膚の中の空気を通して見ることができる
activities in the water
水中でのアクティビティ
this is the same
これも同じです
You see it also uses the skin
皮も使っているのがわかりますね
then in this
それからこの中で
It's in this Middle East
それはこの中東にある
ancient mural above
上にある古代の壁画
accomplished
達成した
So what about the people at that time?
では、当時の人々はどうだったのでしょうか？
He tried to get into the water
彼は水に入ろうとした
to dive
潜る
I'm going to have a look
見てみます
fished something
何かを釣りました
Fishing for antiquities
骨董品を釣る
or go see some
または見に行きます
some other things
他のこと
then this thing
それからこのこと
what about this wish
この願いはどうですか
By 1943
1943年までに
finally come true
ついに叶う
Anyone who knows how to dive now knows
ダイビングの仕方を知っている人なら誰でも知っています。
It is very important that the water fee
水道料金はとても重要です
Now divers will carry this on their backs
これからダイバーはこれを背負っていきます
It is what we usually call the water fee
通常水道料金と呼ばれるものです
it passes through an air
それは空気を通過します
Oxygen level
酸素レベル
Then pass through an air conditioner
その後エアコンを通過します
Then it can breathe in water
そうすれば水中でも呼吸できるようになる
can move in water
水中で移動できる
And this kind of activity can be done freely
そして、このような活動は自由に行うことができます
So this is a very important invention
これは非常に重要な発明です
this is by a french
これはフランス人によるものです
this is the one this is his name
これがこれです、これが彼の名前です
Jack Costow
ジャック・コストウ
such a he is a naval officer
そんな彼は海軍士官だ
He invented the water bill
彼は水道料金を発明した
So he realized this human
それで彼はこの人間に気づきました
able to move underwater
水中を移動できる
such a dream of diving
そんなダイビングの夢
So this is what he invented
それでこれが彼が発明したものです
Such a water fee with two buckets
バケツ2つでこんな水道代
Then the discovery of the water fee for this water
そして、この水の水道料金の発見
This human can go into the water
この人間は水の中に入ることができます
right
右
He can swim freely in the water
彼は水の中を自由に泳ぐことができる
can stay for a while
しばらく滞在できる
can see what he wants to see
彼が見たいものを見ることができる
wants to get what he wants
彼が欲しいものを手に入れたい
then this
それからこれ
but this result
しかしこの結果は
first one of his effects
彼の効果の最初の1つ
that humans can find in water
人間が水中で見つけることができるもの
some ancient cultures should
いくつかの古代文化はそうすべきです
Including ships, buildings, ruins and ancient relics, etc.
船舶、建物、遺跡、古代遺物などを含む。
It is free to discover these things
これらのことを発見するのは無料です
But after discovering
でも発見してからは
become another side effect?
別の副作用になるでしょうか？
Just started a treasure trove
宝探しを始めたばかりです
Everyone goes to the water to find treasure
みんなで宝物を探しに水へ行く
Because everyone knows that there are many treasures in the water
水の中に宝物がたくさんあることは誰もが知っているから
So it has to go to the water to find treasure
だから宝を見つけるために水に行かなければなりません
What about this loot?
この戦利品はどうですか？
still a lot of people
まだたくさんの人が
Still thinking of fishing for treasure
まだ宝釣りを考えています
that this is a recent event
これは最近の出来事だということ
that was in 2007
それは2007年のことでした
America's famous one in Furley
アメリカの有名なファーリー
An ocean exploration company called Odyssey
オデッセイという海洋探査会社
it's this it's a very strong company
これはとても強い会社です
What about its biggest task?
その最大の任務についてはどうでしょうか？
Just go to sea to find these things
これらのものを見つけるために海に行くだけです
Probe, find these undersea safeguards
探査して、海中の安全装置を見つけてください
So it was in 2007 when
それで、それは2007年のことでした。
it's in this spanish in portuguese
これはスペイン語でポルトガル語です
What about the big sunset in the south?
南の空に沈む大きな夕日はどうでしょうか？
it found a boat
それはボートを見つけた
to detect an adult ship
大人の船を検出する
Then go down and do it
じゃあ下に行ってやってみろよ
Lay it down
寝かせて
he hit the city ship
彼はこの街の船を襲った
He named himself Black Swan
彼は自らをブラック・スワンと名付けた
black swan
黒い白鳥
after black swan
ブラックスワンの後
Then this city ship is incredible
それならこの都市の船はすごいよ
what do you see because of him
彼のおかげで何が見えますか
is a gold coin
金貨です
right
右
gold
金
how many gold coins are in it
金貨は何枚入っていますか
There are 500,000 gold coins
金貨は50万枚あります
then this
それからこれ
how much does it add up to
合計するといくらになりますか
There are 17 tons
17トンあります
So that's a big one-coin fortune
それは大きなワンコイン財産です
but it is
しかし、それは
caught in the Atlantic
大西洋に捕らえられた
But its wealth caused
しかし、その富が引き起こしたのは、
Protests in Spain
スペインでの抗議活動
because spanish says
スペイン語が言うから
the boat
ボート
it's their boat
それは彼らのボートです
called mercedes
メルセデスと呼ばれる
this is what they are
ここが彼らのいる場所です
when the british fought
イギリス人が戦ったとき
a ship silent in the atlantic
大西洋で沈黙する船
This ship is sailing back to Spain from South America
この船は南米からスペインに戻る途中です
Then there was silence in the middle
そして途中で沈黙があった
so they want to ask
それで彼らは聞きたいのです
This thing has to be returned to the devil
これは悪魔に返さなければなりません
Spain
スペイン
then this thing
それならこの件
of course until now
もちろん今まで
no big lawsuit for it yet
まだ大きな訴訟は起きていない
big lawsuit
大きな訴訟
during that period
その期間中に
this peru
このペルー
Miru is also asking why
ミルも理由を聞いている
He said you shipped this thing from Miru
彼はこれをミルから送ったと言いました
Then you were not unified by our Miru people
それなら、あなたは私たちのミルの人々によって統一されませんでした
You're shipped to Spain
あなたはスペインに送られます
Spain just said it's not okay
スペインは「大丈夫ではない」とだけ言った
Because you were my colony at the time
だってあなたは当時私の植民地だったから
You are not a sovereign state yourself
あなた自身は主権国家ではありません
so you have no right to ask
だからあなたには質問する権利はない
So now the lawsuit is still going on
それで現在も訴訟は続いている
This also involves American diplomacy and politics
これにはアメリカの外交と政治も関係する
Because the US government is supporting Spain
アメリカ政府がスペインを支援しているから
But this Audis company
しかし、このアウディという会社は、
He is a very powerful private
彼は非常に強力な民間人です
he is very powerful
彼はとてもパワフルです
so he found a lot of lawyers
それで彼はたくさんの弁護士を見つけた
then think american
それからアメリカ人を考えてください
Why don't you favor us Americans
なぜ私たちアメリカ人を支持しないのですか
to support Spain
スペインを応援するために
So he thinks these American governments are a conspiracy
つまり彼は、これらのアメリカ政府は陰謀だと考えている
because of what
何かのせいで
Because the US government wants to get a painting back from Spain
米国政府がスペインから絵画を取り戻したいと考えているため
an ancient painting
古代の絵画
so make an exchange
それで交換してください
So it's in the middle so far
ということで、今のところは真ん中です
Some lawsuits are still pending
一部の訴訟はまだ係争中である
So this also shows
したがって、これも示しています
In fact underwater he is one of many of these ancient safeguards
実際、水中では彼は古代の安全装置の 1 つです。
So actually until now
それで実は今まで
everyone still wants
誰もがまだ望んでいます
He wanted to catch these ancient humans in the water
彼は古代人類を水中で捕まえたかったのです
legacy safeguards
レガシーセーフガード
so this thing has a lot of
それで、これにはたくさんのものが含まれています
until now
今まで
What I said is that we still have them in Taiwan.
私が言ったのは、台湾にはまだ残っているということです。
many people who can dive
ダイビングできる人がたくさんいる
He wanted to fish for some ancient porcelain from the bottom of the sea
彼は海の底から古代の磁器を釣り出したいと思っていました。
can be exchanged for money
お金と交換できる
So this has aroused some people's attention
それで、これは一部の人々の注目を集めました
because of this
このため
Although there are many of these under the sea
海中にはたくさんあるのに
But after these people kept going down to salvage
しかし、その後も人々は引き揚げに下っていきました
These things will all come to naught
こういったものはすべて無になるだろう
They were all taken away by individuals
それらはすべて個人によって持ち去られました
so therefore
だからだから
The country I visited feels
訪れた国が感じたこと
we should make some laws
私たちはいくつかの法律を作るべきです
to protect these underwater
これらを水中で守るために
so-called cultural heritage
いわゆる文化遺産
Then the UK first in 1973
その後、1973年にイギ​​リスで初めて
That's 30 years after the water bill was invented in 1943
1943 年に水道料金が制定されてから 30 年後のことです
At the beginning, the United Kingdom established this traditional protection law
当初、英国はこの伝統的な保護法を制定しました。
Just to protect these Chen Chuan
チェン・チュアンを守るためだけに
Then his Chen Chuan
それから彼のチェン・チュアン
According to Chen Chuan's historical archaeological and artistic value
陳川の歴史的考古学的および芸術的価値によると
then want to specify
次に指定したいのは
After the designation, the government will have power
指定後は政府が権限を持つようになる
to protect it
それを守るために
That is
あれは
that thing
その事
Well
良い
then this
それからこれ
By 1982
1982年までに
What about the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea?
国連海洋法条約についてはどうですか？
He also started to define this, this, this clause
彼はまた、これ、これ、この条項を定義し始めました
It is to require that the protection of sea discoveries has cultural asset value
海洋発見の保護には文化財的価値があることを義務付けること
and items of historical value
歴史的価値のある品々や
it was 1982
1982年のことでした
The United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea
国連海洋法条約
Also set such a
このようなものも設定します
uh a law
ああ、法律
then 1988
その後1988年
the International Law Association
国際法協会
ah
ああ
What about the IRA?
IRAについてはどうですか？
He also started noticing the problem
彼もその問題に気づき始めた
So he also planned to fry a draft convention on underwater cultural assets
そこで彼は水中文化財に関する条約草案を作成することも計画した
he is the draft
彼はドラフトです
ah
ああ
a draft
ドラフト
But it didn't turn into a formal
でも正式なものにはならなかった
a law
法律
Then in 1990
それから1990年に
This international stock machine and a group of federations
この国際ストックマシンと連盟のグループ
This one is at Ecmo in Rome, Italy
これはイタリアのローマにある Ecmo にあります
Well he uh
まあ彼はええと
in 1996
1996年に
He also passed a current chapter called the Management of Underwater Cultural Assets Conservation
彼はまた、水中文化財保存管理と呼ばれる現在の章にも合格しました。
Charter on the protection and management of
の保護と管理に関する憲章
and the water culture heritage
そして水文化遺産
then this is a
それならこれは
in 1990
1990年に
There is a formal
公式もあるよ
There is such an international
こんなインターナショナルもあるんですね
protection of underwater heritage
水中遺産の保護
such a chatter
そんなおしゃべり
Then in 2001
そして2001年に
Finally our United Nations
ついに私たちの国連が
He is passing a called
彼は電話をかけています
I
私
The UNESCO of the United Nations
国連ユネスコ
UNESCO
ユネスコ
Convention on the Protection of the Underwater Cultural Heritage
水中文化遺産の保護に関する条約
So this is enough to see
なのでこれだけ見れば十分です
What about this underwater?
この水中はどうでしょうか？
Actually very late
実はとても遅いのです
until recently
最近まで
you see the 21st century
あなたには21世紀が見えます
and then slowly
そしてゆっくりと
everyone should pay attention
誰もが注意を払うべきです
to protect these underwater
これらを水中で守るために
these human heritage
これらの人類の遺産
the unesco convention
ユネスコ条約
After this mud
この泥の後
Many countries cannot be consecutive
多くの国は連続することができません
because it must have
あるはずだから
After 20 countries in a row
20か国連続出場後
This agreement will come into force
この協定は発効します
why
なぜ
because like many countries
なぜなら多くの国と同じように
for self benefit
自分の利益のために
like just america
まるでアメリカのように
The United States and other countries have many large consortia
米国やその他の国には多くの大規模なコンソーシアムがある
Specially on stage
特別にステージ上で
after the treaty of interest
利権条約の後
it's over
終わりました
So the U.S. government has never dared to sign this
したがって、米国政府はこれまであえて署名しなかった
dare not sign
あえて署名しないでください
That's why I haven't been able to make up enough
だから十分に補うことができなかった
Not enough to make up the number of this country
この国の数を補うには十分ではありません
until January 2009
2009年1月まで
barely enough
かろうじて十分
has just come into effect
発効したばかりです
So now every country in the world
だから今、世界中のどの国も
It wants to protect its underwater cultural heritage
水中文化遺産を保護したいと考えています
must be subject to this convention
この規約に従わなければなりません
as a basis for it
その基礎として
So so according to this convention
この慣例によればまあまあ
So our underwater cultural heritage
私たちの水中文化遺産
What is probably the cultural heritage of hydration
おそらく水分補給の文化遺産は何でしょう
it has a definition
それには定義があります
Then he said underwater cultural heritage
それから彼は水中文化遺産について言いました
it is partially or fully underwater
部分的または完全に水中にあります
periodic or continuous existence
周期的または継続的に存在する
at least 100 years
少なくとも100年は
Just 100 years ago
ちょうど100年前
At the same time it has contained content that contains
同時に、以下の内容が含まれています。
Refers to building houses, handicrafts
家を建てたり手工芸品を指します
human remains
人間の遺体
and its archaeological and natural drama
そしてその考古学的および自然のドラマ
The second is ships, aircraft
2つ目は船舶、航空機です。
and other means of transport
およびその他の交通手段
or any part of the above three categories
または上記 3 つのカテゴリのいずれかの部分
goods or other items
商品またはその他のアイテム
archaeological and natural drama
考古学と自然のドラマ
prehistoric animals
先史時代の動物
Then this is in the underwater heritage protection apartment of the United Nations
そして、これは国連の水中遺産保護アパートにあります
What are these defined underwater heritage
これらの定義された水中遺産とは何ですか
Of course, like the cables we often use in our oceans now
もちろん、私たちが今海でよく使っているケーブルのように
Some of these seabeds are still used
これらの海底の一部は今でも使用されています
Like the earthquake predictor we recently deployed off the coast of Yinan
最近宜南沖に配備した地震予知装置のように
Of course this doesn't count because it's modern.
もちろん、現代のものなのでこれは当てはまりません。
So in the past, if there were 100 years
だから昔、100年あったとしたら
These things probably need to be protected.
これらのものはおそらく保護される必要があります。
the heritage of these cultures
これらの文化の遺産
Well, in this 100 years, there have been new political theories recently
さて、この 100 年の間に、最近新しい政治理論が生まれました。
Especially just saw Katanic
特にカタニックを見たばかりです
After many people on the Katani went fishing
カタニに乗った多くの人が釣りに行った後、
Now it needs to be changed to a later date, about 50 years
現在は、約 50 年後の日付に変更する必要があります。
can have the heritage of these cultures that need to be protected
保護する必要があるこれらの文化の遺産を持っている可能性があります
Well, the invention of the water fee except this
さて、これ以外の水道料金の発明
About fishing insurance involving underwater
水中漁業保険について
In addition to the protection of underwater cultural heritage?
水中文化遺産の保護に加えて?
What about another effect?
別の効果についてはどうでしょうか？
It is this archaeology that has emerged as a new field
新しい分野として登場したのがこの考古学です
Because archeology in the past was all on land
昔の考古学はすべて陸上にあったものだから
Archaeologists dig with shovels
考古学者がシャベルで掘る
But now archaeologists need to go into the water
しかし今、考古学者は水の中に入らなければなりません
That's why it's called underwater archaeology.
それが水中考古学と呼ばれる理由です。
Well, underwater archeology didn't really appear until the 1960s.
そうですね、水中考古学が本格的に登場したのは 1960 年代になってからです。
This is an American archaeologist named George Bath
これはジョージ・バースというアメリカの考古学者です
Well he's retired now
まあ彼はもう引退したけどね
He is a professor at the University of Texas AMM in the United States
彼は米国のテキサス大学 AMM の教授です。
then he retired
それから彼は引退した
I kept in touch with him until recently
私は最近まで彼と連絡を取り続けていました
He is considered the father of underwater archaeology
彼は水中考古学の父とみなされています
a founder
一個founder
Well, he's first in the Turkish waters on the south side
そうですね、彼は最初に南側のトルコ海域に入りました
called Cabidonia for underwater surveys
水中調査のためにカビドニアと呼ばれる
He's investigating East Rome
彼は東ローマを調査している
These are the city legends of the Byzantine period
これらはビザンチン時代の都市伝説です
Discover a wealth of these cultural relics from the Byzantine era
ビザンチン時代の豊富な文化遺物を発見
So for us to understand these Byzantine eras from the Eastern Roman era
東ローマ時代からビザンチン時代を理解するには
The traffic of these past seas
過去の海の往来
The production of these trades at the time
当時のこれらの貿易の生産
Korean technology and so on
韓国の技術など
He provided some important
彼はいくつかの重要な情報を提供してくれました
some new information
いくつかの新しい情報
So this is considered a very important one
したがって、これは非常に重要なことだと考えられています
A job in underwater archeology
水中考古学の仕事
then this
それからこれ
This is where he was at the time
ここが当時彼がいた場所です
south coast of Türkiye
トゥルキエの南海岸
The archaeological work carried out
行われた考古学的作業
he is totally one
彼は完全に一人です
Here's what he collected for research
これが彼が研究のために集めたものです
This map of this MAP
このMAPのこのMAP
look at these wrecks found
見つかったこれらの残骸を見てください
So wait a minute
それで、ちょっと待ってください
Well, he is using a very scientific method
そうですね、彼は非常に科学的な手法を使っています
to carry out underwater
水中で実行する
instead of big fish
大きな魚の代わりに
He is an underwater archaeologist
彼は水中考古学者です
that is very systematic
それはとても体系的です
From a scientific point of view?
科学的な観点から?
to carry out underwater cultural relics?
水中文化財を運び出すには？
to collect
集める
record
記録
to investigate
調べる
so so
まあまあ
Now we get into this underwater archeology
さあ、水中考古学に入りましょう
Because of this, after all, Taiwan has not
このため、結局のところ、台湾は
so i thought i would like to slightly
だから少ししたいと思った
can introduce
紹介できる
What is underwater archaeology?
水中考古学とは何ですか?
It's actually archaeology
実は考古学なんです
It basically its principles and some of its methods
基本的にその原理とそのいくつかの方法
basically the same as archeology
基本的には考古学と同じ
But some of its tools use
ただし、そのツールの一部では
the equipment it uses
それが使用する機器
Of course, the environment of archaeology on the road is different.
もちろん、考古学の現場では環境が異なります。
So therefore it's not the same as this
したがって、これは同じではありません
So underwater archeology it's all about combining diving equipment
つまり、水中考古学はダイビング装備の組み合わせがすべてなのです
and Ocean Exploration Technology
海洋探査技術と
By investigating and discovering
調べて発見することで
Submerged ship ruins and relics, etc.
水没した船の遺跡や遺物など。
To study the history and culture of human beings in the past
過去の人類の歴史や文化を学ぶ
So it's going to combine diving
それでダイビングを組み合わせるつもりです
and some marine exploration equipment
およびいくつかの海洋探査機器
and other disciplines
および他の分野
Come and do these underwater
さあ、水中でやってみよう
Relic and ship detection work
遺物と船舶の探知作業
job found
仕事が見つかりました
So so as an underwater archaeologist
水中考古学者としてはそうだ
It's more complicated than this terrestrial archeology
この地球考古学よりも複雑です
It's road archeology is already complicated
道路考古学はすでに複雑です
But underwater archeology
しかし、水中考古学
The environment in which it works is inside the water
水中で動作する環境に対応します。
so it's more complicated
だからもっと複雑です
it has to be a team job
それはチームの仕事でなければなりません
so it includes more than just archaeologists
したがって、考古学者以外の人々も含まれます
Ocean explorer Marine engineer Historian Marine geologist
海洋探検家 海洋技術者 歴史家 海洋地質学者
Ancient tomb maintenance scientists, communication personnel, diving workers, etc.
古墳維持管理者、通信員、潜水員など
It is a teamwork, not a job that any individual can perform
チームワークであり、1人でできる仕事ではありません
This picture is a typical underwater archaeological work
この写真は典型的な水中考古学的作品です
You see there must be a working platform above the water
水の上に作業台があるはずです
If the following archaeological excavations are carried out,
以下のような考古学的発掘が行われると、
So it still has to follow the archaeological method
したがって、依然として考古学的手法に従わなければなりません
Some principles to do these archaeological work
こうした考古学的作業を行うためのいくつかの原則
Then all these unearthed cultural relics
そして、これらすべての発掘された文化遺物は、
It must be transported to the sea in a welfare bag like a welfare bag
福祉バッグのような福祉バッグに入れて海まで運ばなければなりません
it's a part job
それはパートの仕事です
Then go back and there are some unearthed cultural relics and some maintenance
それから戻ると、発掘された文化遺物といくつかのメンテナンスがあります
Because the preservation environment of underwater cultural relics is very different from that on the road
水中文化財の保存環境は道路上とは大きく異なるため
Regardless of the water pressure, regardless of the environment of the water body
水圧に関係なく、水域の環境に関係なく
basically very different
基本的には大きく異なります
So once things come out of the water
ですから、物事が水から出てくると、
to be maintained immediately
すぐにメンテナンスされる
Otherwise it will be destroyed immediately
そうしないとすぐに破壊されます
so therefore
だからだから
This artifact is preserved in Underwater Archeology
この遺物は水中考古学に保存されています
is also a very important part
も非常に重要な部分です
so so so
それでなぜ
What about underwater archaeology?
水中考古学についてはどうですか？
It does more than just discover shipwrecks
難破船を発見するだけではありません
or pick up the items
またはアイテムを拾う
Instead, we need to use the context of underwater archaeological data
代わりに、水中考古学的データのコンテキストを使用する必要があります。
To study the human cultural legacy related to the ocean
海洋に関する人類の文化遺産を研究する
including social economy political religion
社会経済・政治・宗教を含む
Legacy at various levels
さまざまなレベルのレガシー
and its environmental factors
とその環境要因
It's an underwater archeology
それは水中考古学です
So what about underwater archaeology?
では、水中考古学はどうでしょうか？
it is very important
それは非常に重要です
It is important in several ways
いろいろな意味で重要です
The first is of course an important cultural
一つ目はもちろん重要な文化です
What about underwater cultural relics?
水中文化財はどうでしょうか？
It has quite a few assets that are an important cultural
重要文化財が数多く残っている
why
なぜ
Because these things are in the sea
こういったものは海の中にあるので、
It is a flotant
フロータントです
also by a frozen wave of time
凍りついた時間の波によっても
Everything stops at that time
その時すべてが止まる
so anything in it
だからその中にあるものは何でも
it can reflect
反映できる
All the real conditions at that time
当時のすべての実際の状況
So therefore it is a very important cultural asset
したがって、非常に重要な文化財です
At the same time, it certainly has very important academic research value
同時に、それは確かに非常に重要な学術研究的価値を持っています
Because underwater remains often provide us with a lot in our archives
なぜなら、水中遺跡は私たちのアーカイブに多くの情報を提供してくれることが多いからです。
Some new information that was not there
そこにはなかったいくつかの新しい情報
These messages may not be in any mean documentation file
これらのメッセージは、いかなる文書ファイルにも含まれていない可能性があります。
But it can exist in the remains of these substances unearthed from underwater
しかし、水中から発掘されたこれらの物質の残骸には存在する可能性があります
Can tell us a lot of various information
いろいろな情報をたくさん教えてもらえる
Including the agreement of the individual to that of the whole group
グループ全体の同意に個人の同意を含む
or from something tiny to a large group itself
または小さなものから大きなグループ自体まで
These engineering techniques and so on
こういった工学技術などは
And the development of the entire history of human culture
そして人類文化の歴史全体の発展
It can often provide some very important information
多くの場合、非常に重要な情報が提供されることがあります
In addition, of course, the underwater cultural heritage is now
また、水中文化遺産はもちろん、
It is also a very important tourist resource.
とても重要な観光資源でもあります。
So now many countries are also developing underwater museums
現在、多くの国が水中博物館を開発しています。
Like this mainland-like Three Gorges in Egypt
この本土のようなエジプトの三峡のように
after it was flooded by the reservoir
貯水池に浸水した後
Some are in the water and it builds an underwater museum
水中には水中博物館が建てられることもある
You can also go to the water to see
水辺に行って見ることもできます
so it can attract a lot of these tourists
多くの観光客を惹きつけることができる
Now also advocate this so-called diving tourism
現在はこのいわゆるダイビングツーリズムも提唱しています
There are some city ships that allow spectators to allow tourists to approach
観光客が近づくことを許可する観客を許可する都市船もいくつかあります
you can go snorkeling at home
家でシュノーケリングができる
Or diving can come close to these underwater
または、ダイビングでこれらの水中に近づくことができます
The remains of these fascinating ancient cultures
これらの魅力的な古代文化の遺跡
It has also become a very important tourist resource
とても重要な観光資源にもなっています
like our yap island in the pacific
太平洋のヤップ島のように
Saipan in the Taipei Ocean
台北の海のサイパン
These all look like this
これらはすべてこんな感じです
These are very economically beneficial
これらは経済的に非常に有益です
such a benefit
そのような利点
I thought I'd give a quick introduction to underwater archeology
水中考古学について簡単に紹介しようと思いました
Underwater archaeology is actually the same method as land archaeology
水中考古学は実際には陸上考古学と同じ方法です
It also includes the collection of research information for the project
プロジェクトの研究情報の収集も含まれます。
Underwater archaeological investigation and excavation
水中考古学調査・発掘
Finally, there is maintenance and placement of water cultural relics
最後に、水の文化遺物の維持と配置もあります。
Also research interpretation presentation and publication
研究解釈発表・出版も
Then this is as an underwater archeology
これは水中考古学として
Underwater archeology requires a very careful planning
水中考古学には非常に慎重な計画が必要です
These plans include its scope of purpose
これらの計画にはその目的の範囲が含まれています
Tactics, methods, cost of personnel, equipment, and laws
戦術、方法、人件費、設備、法律
because it is a cultural asset
文化財なので
After entering, the water must comply with the legal norms
水に入った後は法的基準を遵守する必要があります
In addition, there is actually an ecological
さらに、実は生態学的にも
Because underwater work cannot damage the existing underwater ecological environment
水中での作業は既存の水中の生態環境を破壊することができないため、
So these things have to go through a very careful planning
したがって、これらのことは非常に慎重な計画を経る必要があります
to be able to execute
実行できるようにする
So our regulations are quite strict
したがって、私たちの規制は非常に厳しいです
Now Taiwan we are firing you
台湾よ、あなたを解雇します
Underwater Cultural Assets Preservation Act
水中文化財保存法
This file will already fire one of your bills
このファイルはすでに請求書の 1 つを発行します
Currently still in the Executive Yuan
現在も行政院にいる
After the Executive Yuan passed it, it was called Soli Court
行政院が可決した後、それはソリ裁判所と呼ばれた
and then pass
そして通過します
So this is the collection of information
ということで情報収集です
Well, underwater archeology is not just about going underwater.
さて、水中考古学は単に水中に潜ることだけではありません。
Actually it requires a lot of related work
実際には多くの関連作業が必要です
So it's a fairly labor-intensive
なので、かなり手間がかかる作業です
it needs to be dictated
それは口述する必要がある
Because many underwater messages are not necessarily given the file
多くの水中メッセージには必ずしもファイルが与えられるわけではないため、
Oral data instead
代わりに口頭データ
can tell us a lot about this
これについてたくさん教えてください
So local fishermen are like sailors
つまり、地元の漁師は船員のようなものです
This kind of sailors, etc.
こんな船員さんたちなど。
They will have a lot of information
彼らはたくさんの情報を持っているでしょう
Come tell us about the underwater
水中について教えてください
what they met i saw
彼らが出会ったこと、私が見たこと
some underwater remnants of some culture
ある文化の水中に残ったもの
like especially fishermen
特に漁師のように
he sometimes trawls
彼は時々トロールする
Or he, a fisherman's reconnaissance machine
あるいは彼、漁師の偵察機
You will find a lot of underwater
水中にはたくさんのものが見つかります
Target
目標
Then he will record again
それから彼はまた録音するでしょう
especially some shipwrecks
特にいくつかの難破船
because he often trawls
彼はよくトロールをするので
broke his net
彼の網を破った
So fishermen hate the entrance
だから漁師たちは入り口を嫌う
hate very much
とても嫌い
So he'll just jot that down
それで彼はそれを書き留めるでしょう
So the next time he goes
それで、次に彼が行くときは
don't go past that point
その点を超えないでください
These points are often second to us
これらの点はしばしば私たちにとって二の次です
becomes an important
重要になります
valuable information
貴重な情報
because he told you there's something over there
そこに何かがあるって彼が言ったから
he may be a shipwreck
彼は難破船かもしれない
maybe a big rock
大きな岩かもしれない
But at least it's a potential target
しかし、少なくともそれは潜在的なターゲットです
Also some food information
グルメ情報も
This information contains archaeological information on these roads
この情報には、これらの道路に関する考古学的情報が含まれています
because the boat is in the sea
船は海の中なので
Tend to be affected by the waves will be affected by some factors
波の影響を受けやすい 何らかの要因で影響を受ける
Will bring some parts to land
一部の部品を陸地に運びます
There will be some ancient porcelain on the coast
海岸には古代の磁器があるでしょう
or something on board
または船上の何か
these things are some clues
これらはいくつかの手がかりです
So when we investigated Pongpo
そこでポンポで調査したところ
These porcelains from the Yuan Dynasty can be found at the seaside
海辺で見つかる元代の磁器
Tell us there must be these wrecks nearby
近くにこれらの難破船があるに違いないと教えてください
These shipwrecks are the ones we haven't found yet.
これらの難破船は私たちがまだ発見していないものです。
Or the past has been washed away by the waves
それとも過去は波にさらわれてしまったのか
then this is a
それならこれは
In addition, of course, the information of Wenwen County is still very important.
また、当然のことですが、文文県の情報は依然として非常に重要です。
We're going to start with some files
いくつかのファイルから始めます
Find some clues from some historical documents
いくつかの歴史的文書からヒントを見つける
In addition, the geographical environment
また、地理的環境も
Because of these places where the shipwreck
難破船が沈没した場所のせいで
It is related to the geographical environment
それは地理的環境が関係している
near these are mountain peppers
これらの近くには山椒があります
There is a diving beach
ダイビングビーチがあります
Hazardous glue
危険な接着剤
these things
これらの事
There are still very fluid in these environments
これらの環境では依然として非常に流動的です
strong current
強い電流
Ocean currents can cause these shipwrecks
海流はこれらの難破船を引き起こす可能性があります
produced by a place
場所によって生み出される
So these data are very important to us
したがって、これらのデータは私たちにとって非常に重要です
Then this as a look
それからこれは見た目として
This is after we use various information
様々な情報を活用した上でのことです
Like our investigation in Penghu
澎湖での調査のように
Let's temporarily locate these possible potentials
これらの潜在的な可能性を一時的に見つけてみましょう
some possible locations
いくつかの考えられる場所
Potential existence and existence
潜在的な存在と存在
or this location of the submerged target
または水没目標のこの場所
Then we are going to use this information
そして、これらの情報をもとに、
To do this underwater credible survey
この信頼できる水中調査を行うには
investigation
調査
vast sea
広大な海
That needle in the haystack
干し草の山の中のあの針
We can't go to all the oceans
私たちはすべての海に行くことはできません
do the research
研究をする
go to sea as a sister
妹として海に行く
When you go into the sea, you feel like a tree in the ocean
海に入ると、まるで海の中の木になったような気分になります
to the vast sea
広大な海へ
My home is too small
私の家は小さすぎる
then you have to do the research
それなら調査をしなければなりません
how to do the investigation
調査をどのように行うか
right
右
Of course we're fine now
もちろん今は大丈夫です
good technology now
今は良い技術がある
So this underwater archaeological team
それでこの水中考古学チームは
We'll include these experts in ocean exploration
これらの専門家を海洋探査に参加させます
Instruments that help exploit these detections
これらの検出を悪用するのに役立つ手段
to help us discover some possible
いくつかの可能性を発見するのに役立ちます
some potential targets
いくつかの潜在的なターゲット
Now our most commonly used is SizeGain
現在、最も一般的に使用されているのは SizeGain です
SizeGain Zona
サイズゲインゾナ
Scanning Sodium
ナトリウムをスキャンする
it uses a sound wave
音波を使用します
This sonic instrument
この音響楽器は
Come hit the ship from that
そこから船にぶつかって来てください
and then reflect back
そして振り返ります
look at this sonic
このソニックを見てください
to sonic
ソニックへ
Then found that there may be some
その後、いくつかの可能性があることがわかりました
this target
このターゲット
Another sound measurement system called polysonic
ポリソニックベロシティと呼ばれる別の音響測定システム
Called MatiBing System
MatiBing システムと呼ばれる
This is called the sound measuring system
これを音響測定システムといいます
This is also a principle of using a sound wave
これも音波を利用する原理です
Of course it can find
もちろん見つけられるよ
Some of the following possible targets
以下の考えられるターゲットの一部
In addition, this Strata Instant Noodle Apparatus
なお、このストラータ即席麺装置は、
叫Subbutton Provider
サブボタンプロバイダーの呼び出し
This Stratum Instant Noodle Apparatus uses this
このストラタム即席麺装置はこれを使用しています
use the seabed above
上の海底を利用する
Many of them were buried by the seabed and sea sand.
その多くは海底や海砂に埋もれていました。
You only rely on these two instruments in front of you
頼れるのは目の前のこの二つの楽器だけ
dare not find it
あえて見つけないでください
Because it's buried at a meter two meters
1メートル2メートル埋まってるから
In the mud three meters below
3メートル下の泥の中
Therefore, you can use this Strata Instant Noodle Apparatus
したがって、このストラタム即席麺装置を使用できます。
can go deeper
より深く進むことができます
to discover what's buried beneath the seabed
海底の下に何が埋まっているのかを発見するために
possible target
可能性のあるターゲット
Unmanned remote control front distance
無人リモコン正面距離
There's something this pretty deep
なかなか奥深いものがありますね
People still can't get down
人々はまだ降りられない
At this time we can use this so-called ROV
現時点では、このいわゆるROVを使用できます
Can use remote control
リモコンが使える
It's like a robot
まるでロボットのようだ
You can remotely control the robot to do photography in the water
ロボットを遠隔操作して水中で写真撮影が可能
Now there is a more advanced
今では、より高度な機能があります
unmanned underwater vehicle
無人水中車両
This is remote control
これはリモコンです
This doesn't even need a remote
これならリモコンも要らない
just a robot
ただのロボット
After entering, he can go by himself
入ったら一人で行ける
to take pictures
写真を取ります
so like that titanic
あのタイタニックみたいに
Basically use such a device
基本的にはこのようなデバイスを使用します
Go in and shoot to a depth of 3,000 meters
潜入して深さ3,000メートルまで撃つ
Some of the current status of the Titanic
タイタニック号の現在の状況の一部
There is also a magnetometer
磁力計もあります
This magnetometer is used
この磁力計が使われています
Targets mainly for these metals
主にこれらの金属をターゲットとしています
to detect
検出する
Let's see the abnormal condition of its magnetism
その磁気の異常状態を見てみましょう
to speculate that there may be targets in the ground
地面に標的があるかもしれないと推測する
So these we can use the underwater positioning system
これで水中測位システムを使用できるようになります
and Differential Global Positioning System
および差動全地球測位システム
to define its scope
その範囲を定義する
this target
このターゲット
Then this is the instrument we use when we work
それから、これは私たちが仕事をするときに使う道具です
What about this part, our Academia Sinica team
この部分についてはどうですか、中央研究院チーム。
we have some instruments
私たちはいくつかの楽器を持っています
What about the other part of the instrument?
楽器の他の部分はどうですか？
Also with Sun Yat-Sen University School of Ocean Sciences
中山大学海洋科学部とも連携
We have a combination of a team
チームの組み合わせがあります
let's do it together
一緒にやりましょう
Like this is Mati Bing
これがマティ・ビンです
This is Chief Executive Shengna
最高責任者のシェンナです
This is this Bud, Subbottom Profiler
これがこのつぼみ、サブボトムプロファイラーです
This is the ROV, the unmanned submersible
これがROV、無人潜水艇です
So this basically looks like this
基本的には次のようになります
We towed the instruments behind the boat
私たちはボートの後ろで楽器を牽引しました
and then trace
そして追跡します
Let the above description be very systematic
上記の説明を非常に体系的に説明しましょう
do this
これを行う
So what is more advanced now is to use this
したがって、現在より高度なことは、これを使用することです
Someone
誰か
A small submarine like this one can be built by a human
このような小型潜水艦は人間でも造ることができる
Of course it's a pity we don't have this in Taiwan
もちろん、台湾にこれがないのは残念です
then in the future
それから将来的には
when really needed
本当に必要なとき
maybe we hope
たぶん私たちは願っています
Of course it's expensive and expensive
もちろん高いし高いし
that part
その部分
There is no such
そのようなはありません
Then when we do the investigation next time
じゃあ次回調査するときは
Is it a random investigation?
抜き打ち捜査なのか？
we are still very systematic
私たちはまだ非常に体系的です
Formed into these grades, these Fangke systems
これらのグレードに形成されたこれらの Fangke システム
What can we do with this Fangke system?
このFangkeシステムで何ができるでしょうか?
to do this sampling
このサンプリングを行うには
We can't do it everywhere
どこでもできるわけではない
We can do some sampling in the future
将来的にはサンプリングを行う可能性があります
do it do it do the research
やれ、やれ、調査をやれ
Then the other is us
じゃあ、もう一人は私たちだ
after discovery
発見後
After the discovery of this series
このシリーズを発見してから
We still have to go down by our dive source
私たちはまだダイビングソースのそばまで下らなければなりません
Why
なぜ
Computers are still inferior to human brains
コンピューターはまだ人間の脳より劣っている
right
右
the computer will tell you
コンピューターが教えてくれる
There's a target down here
この下にターゲットがあります
but what is the target
しかし、ターゲットは何ですか
it won't tell you
それはあなたに教えてくれません
It just says there is an anomaly
異常があると言っているだけです
There is something abnormal and a signal appears
異常が発生して信号が表示される
then maybe a
それなら多分
a rock
岩石
maybe a shipwreck
たぶん難破船
maybe a city wall
たぶん城壁
This thing must rely on our divers
これはダイバーに頼らなければなりません
go down and search
下に行って検索してください
It also needs to be very systematic.
また、非常に体系的である必要もあります。
to conduct a survey like this
このような調査を実施するには
It's not just wandering around the bottom
底辺をさまよっているだけではない
then this is
それならこれは
So there are various ways of investigating this
これを調べるにはさまざまな方法があります
including emergent
緊急も含めて
like a linear
直線のように
These diving sources have been lined up
こんなダイビングソースが並んでいます
such investigation or
このように調べたり、
is corridor style
回廊式です
Each person is responsible for a Cathedral and a corridor
各人が大聖堂と回廊を担当します
Or everyone in a circle
あるいはサークル内の全員
Playing circles to do surveys
アンケートを行うためにサークルをプレイする
There is a set of methods
一連のメソッドがあります
In addition we investigate
さらに調査します
Very important is this aerial and satellite photography
この航空写真と衛星写真は非常に重要です
Some of the information provided to us
当社に提供される情報の一部
Now this technology is also very advanced
今ではこの技術も非常に進歩しています
Nearest Central University
最寄りの中央大学
They also want to take advantage of this
彼らもこれを利用したいと考えています
their space instruments
彼らの宇宙機器
to use the temperature
温度を利用する
Let's see if there are any unusual shipwrecks down there.
そこに珍しい難破船がないか見てみましょう。
Or these messages from underwater beings
あるいは水中の存在からのメッセージ
They are also experimenting with this part
彼らはこの部分でも実験中です
like this is
これのように
This is in the Dongsha Islands
ここは東沙諸島です
Above Dongsha Atoll
東沙環礁上空
With this artificial satellite, you can image
この人工衛星を使えば、
It can be seen that in the shallow sea part
浅い海の部分にあるのがわかります。
there are many, many of these
これらはたくさんあります
The possible existence of this shipwreck
この難破船が存在する可能性